<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Chenghao Li&#39;s Space</title>
    <link>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Chenghao Li&#39;s Space</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Online resources for improving english speaking</title>
      <link>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/11/21/online-resources-for-improving-english-speaking/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/11/21/online-resources-for-improving-english-speaking/</guid>
      <description>Obviously, speaking good English is essential to live in the UK. And as a non-native speaker, I often feel there are so many things I need to learn to improve my English speaking skills. Fluency is an important aspect, but not the only thing I should look at. Using the RIGHT works, the way I say it (tone, intonation, accent), and maybe a touch of humor:) can make a huge difference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Football Team Photo</title>
      <link>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/30/football-team-photo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/30/football-team-photo/</guid>
      <description>Today our football team, Warwick Origin Point Football Club (华威原点足球俱乐部), get a photographer coming to our training match and take some photos. Team photo, me at middle in back row</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on the Birmingham Decarbonisation Summer School (BDSS)</title>
      <link>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/30/reflections-on-the-summer-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/30/reflections-on-the-summer-school/</guid>
      <description>Group Photo on Day one in BDSS&#xD;I attended the Birmingham Decarsbonisation Summer School (BDSS) two weeks ago. It was 5 amazing days in the beautiful and historic University of Birmingham. I met some brilliant PhD researchers and post-docs during the event. Industrial experts from National Grid, SSEN, GE Vernova, and many more gave very technical talks. I learnt an awful of insights and knowledge about electrical power system and the challenges the UK&amp;rsquo;s National Grid (NG) is facing in the renewable energy era.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>蔡襄《十三日吉祥院探花》</title>
      <link>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/27/%E8%94%A1%E8%A5%84%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%89%E6%97%A5%E5%90%89%E7%A5%A5%E9%99%A2%E6%8E%A2%E8%8A%B1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/27/%E8%94%A1%E8%A5%84%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%89%E6%97%A5%E5%90%89%E7%A5%A5%E9%99%A2%E6%8E%A2%E8%8A%B1/</guid>
      <description>《十三日吉祥院探花》1 [宋代] 蔡襄2 花未全开月未圆，看花待月思依然。 明知花月无情物，若使多情更可怜。 译文 花还没有全开，月还没有全圆，可我仍旧</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>After I spent over 400 GBP, I realised...</title>
      <link>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/26/after-i-spent-over-400-i-realised/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://chenghaoli1.github.io/post/2024/06/26/after-i-spent-over-400-i-realised/</guid>
      <description>I spent over 400 quid on betting on EURO Cup 2024 and I lost 144. Of course, it might not sound too much, but the point I want to make is not how much I lost rather what lessons I got from it and what YOU can to do avoid. Realisations stroke me last night when I lost 18 consecutive bets. No matter what strategy I use or how smart</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
